hey everyone
welcome to another weekly stock video
so every week i send out a newsletter
which has uh four stocks and these four
stocks are uh basically picked after
some good research especially based on
technicals and fundamentals and i look
for stocks which are you know which have
the potential to give a decent returns
in the short term and probably you know
much better returns in the long term
now after i cherry pick these four
stocks i send out a newsletter which has
uh interesting content especially if you
are
if you're working and you don't have the
time for markets and if you're looking
for some concise short inputs on how you
should be treating your portfolio or how
you should feel about or how the markets
are doing then this newsletter is the
perfect newsletter for you and if you
haven't subscribed yet do subscribe it
right away the link is in the comment
section
okay um so this week i uh also mentioned
uh i did mention why nifty is going so
high and you know just minutes has just
been going up and up and up after every
breakout and i think we are still uh you
know much
i think there's still some time left
before we make a top uh and also i'll
cover you know force talks uh every week
we'll discuss that in detail and that's
the video uh this is the video for that
and also i discuss a series called trend
following series wherein i help people
to understand you know how to
invest in stocks how to trade in stocks
and how to make the best use of strong
trends and for this uh i've been writing
writing a series of articles and this is
the 16th article that i've written the
16th newsletter and it's been 16 weeks
which means i've been writing newsletter
for four months now and i've been
enjoying this and if you're also
enjoying reading it do let me know in
the comment section but if you see the
blog has developed very nicely this also
shows how small effort every week you
know regularly can bring up something as
beautiful as this blog right and this
blog um
this week i've covered the rectangle
pattern uh and i hope you
uh read it and if you do have any doubts
let me know in the comment section and
also i've covered the inverted head and
shoulders and these are the best
patterns that i like to trade uh in
markets
okay um so also uh before we jump into
the stocks uh this is the newsletters uh
sheet where i track all the stock ideas
and uh you know you can find all of them
here with the stop loss with uh the
entry levels and uh you know what is the
current uh return that you're having
what is current rr now it's up to you if
you want to book this book book your
profits i'd leave it completely up to
you but i do uh you know update the stop
loss here so for example we are sitting
on a 2.4 our trade in stove craft uh
even though it's up 20 which means we
risked one rupee we made two and a half
times that money till now um but whereas
we also have the stock which are 45 of
the same rr which means we had a higher
risk there and uh with related with
relation to the risk the reward has been
just two and a half times all right so
it's all about the risk and the reward
in markets so if you're able to
understand that and if you're able to uh
invest based on that then you have
opportunities to make really good money
in markets so let's jump into this
week's talk videos right so the first
talk uh that this week i covered is htfc
as a management company or htfc amc it's
a beautiful stock um technically it's an
excellent stock i i
think it's one of the best stocks and
the finance space uh there are many
other stocks as well but uh don't get me
wrong but this is also one of the best
stocks in the finance in the investing
space and they are a very good company
also okay so the stock was listed back
in uh 2018 and then we had ipo based
breakout so this was the base breakout
here and 2000 from uh into the 19600 we
went all the way up to 3000 so that's
almost double in few months and then we
kind of had a dip after the cover crash
and we had a symmetrical triangle
formation now a symmetrical triangle
formation is nothing but a kind of a
spring where the price contracts over a
period of time and then the price
expands right so this was a price
contraction and then we had a price
expansion now that's how markets are
right so markets sometimes uh price
markets uh the price of the share goes
down sometime it goes up but uh the
moves up is what you have to focus on
and these are the patterns that you have
to focus on to catch those moves right
for example a base breakout a beautiful
100 move here here again we had a 30
move so returns do change depending on
the patterns right but this was a nice
breakout and also we had a higher high
here and we broke a number and we went
all the way up
and since then we've been forming a nice
base and it's the eight month base and i
think the stock is kind of getting uh
prepping itself to head higher from here
and that's the reason why i covered this
talk it's a nice pattern um on the
weekly charts it's a beautiful setup to
trade and it's just a continuation
pattern if this is a breakout and that's
a continuation
or a consolidation here and if you have
a breakout that's a continuation
breakout now a lot of people uh i've
seen have drawn the trend line here
which is also fine which is just totally
fine and they see a breakout here but at
least that's not how i am looking at it
i'm looking at the breakout here first
and then this is consolidation and then
we have a construction breakout so
that's the first talk uh if you want to
look for the targets go back and check
in the newsletter but that's the
technical reason that i covered now what
is the fundamental reason that this
stock is bound to do well right so the
fundamental reason
is uh first of all this company is a
debt free company it has a very good
operating margin 80 which means uh if
they have 100 rupee sales they make 80
rupees operating profits and it is a
very good bad even for the long term and
has an excellent roc which means if the
company deploys one rupee probably it's
making very good money out of that one
rupee which is deployed and the
operating margins have grown from 57 in
2018 to 80 in 2021. so that's the
primary reason from a fundamental
perspective and the technical
perspective is that we had a nice
breakout and a consolidation now and
again probably the breakout is going to
head higher so that's the first talk and
i know many of you would already be
holding this
company since ipo
because this is a very good company to
hold and if you are holding and if you
have any of the reasons apart from the
reasons that i've mentioned do let me
know in the comment section i'd be happy
to discuss that feature
so the second company today we're
looking at is icc lumbar general
insurance company which is also from the
finance space but this is more from the
insurance space
so again a beautiful setup here
um so i see ici
lumbar okay so here i'm going to the
monthly chart just to show you this
channel right so this is a this talk
again was listed in 2018 and 2017 and
it's been a beautiful uptrend and this
stock would have already given decent
returns if you've been holding since ipo
it's already up almost two and a half x
right so 650 to almost 1600 so
yeah not two and a half x probably yeah
lesser than that so right now this what
the stock is doing it's kind of having a
breakout uh out of this all-time high
the previous high uh breakout was in the
month of uh jan 21 uh you know we kind
of reversed and went all the way high
and we're kind of consolidating and now
we are prepping up to move higher now
now this stock is in a nice parallel
channel and until this panel channel
doesn't break you can also consider the
stock for long term investment so
probably this can just keep going higher
like this or it can go and break out
from here as well so it's a very good
point to enter the stock right now the
risk is very less and probably you can
have a good return in the coming years
okay so that's the second stock um
that's the technical reason for this
talk just going to the weekly charts you
would see that this much better you can
see that this is probably another
symmetrical triangle which we are
looking at on the weekly charts right so
that's probably another symmetrical
triangle now
from a fundamental perspective most of
us know this is a very good company it's
part of the icc bank group and it's in
the private general private instrument
space but one thing that i've noticed
here is firs have been continuously
increasing the stake since it was listed
in fact you can go and check the numbers
on screener.n uh the numbers are really
there and you can really see that
numbers and it also had a very excellent
financial 2021 uh it had increasing
sales and profits and the operating
margins also increased from 12 in 17
2017 to 16
in 2021 so that's the fundamental reason
if there's anything that i'm missing
from a fundamental perspective i'd be
more than happy to learn from you uh do
let me know in the comment section and
if you're investing also do let me know
so the third stock again is from the
finance space and this is angel broking
it's a very new company in the markets
uh it was listed just this year and it's
in a phenomenal it has had a phenomenal
run since the ipo base
uh so since it was listed it never went
below that listing price just for a few
days probably but since october the
stock has more than gone up 4x right
since uh you know from the blows if you
consider almost 6x from the lows okay
but for us we always focus on technical
patterns uh we don't want to buy the
bottoms we don't want to sit in the tops
so it was had a nice base breakout here
again in the month of may and since may
it also has gone up 3x from 400 to 1200
but if you see there's a beautiful
trendline support
which is
again providing support here and i feel
that this consolidation it's just a
consolidation after this move from here
right from 800 200 1400 and it's just
consolidating and i think that this
consolidation is over and probably we
are heading higher
towards levels of you know even 1500 odd
levels in the short term and again it's
a fantastic company
to be invested in probably in for the
long run uh who knows but always keep a
stop loss and that would save you from
losing much of your capital now let's
look at the fundamental reasoning the
fundamental reasoning is uh is simple uh
it has been posting excel numbers in the
last few quarters and it increases
revenue by 50
from 2020 you know from 748 in 201 2020
to 1290 in 2021. that's 50 increase in
sales right and also profits kind of
went 4x from 114 crores to 410 crores
and the operating margins include 50
from 24 36
so
if you're looking at such a company and
you don't invest i think that's um
i i think probably might have other
companies but uh after looking such a
company uh i at least not miss investing
at right at this point so that's the
fundamental reasoning from my
perspective again if i'm missing
something do let me know in the comment
section i'd be more than happy to
understand your perspective
okay the fourth talk is from the
commodity space gravity india now this
is again another interesting stock
because this is closing uh it's almost
close to a multi-year breakout now when
i mean multi-year breakout here it is
from 2012 the stock has literally not
done anything since existing it's just
been going sideways so if you bought in
2012 uh you're still sitting in losses
or probably in minor profits right but
this is stock but this stock is close to
a multi resistance and this is a perfect
horizontal resistance and a breakout
from here would mean that the stock can
even double or triple from this point
right now again just because i'm saying
it's going to double or triple don't
just invest all your money in this and
you know uh keep trying that the stock
is not moving that's not how it works
you need to probably allocate five
percent or 10 percent or higher
percentage if you're if you understand
markets and then invest in the stock
right but it's a beautiful setup i think
it has a very good potential if it
crosses above 210 220 um that would be a
very good closing and from there we can
see the stock doing very very well now
that's a technical perspective if you
think uh you have any other reasons to
let me know uh the from from sorry from
a fundamental perspective uh you know
even though say the share price hasn't
moved much the company has managed to
improve sales from 160 crores to 1400
crores while the share price has not
gone anywhere
right that shows why this share is
probably undervalued and also profits
increase from 12 to 50 to crores in the
same period right now when the share
price has not done anything the company
has done exceedingly well there could be
reasons why this stock is not moving
could be some reasons but i think that
reason is right now probably not valid
anymore and it can probably head higher
from here remember this is the commodity
space so usually stocks in the commodity
space can do really well and i feel this
might also do really well going forward
so that's the fourth stock and uh that's
the last talk that i want to discuss
today so if you did
love my analysis uh i'm sure you learned
at least something if you did not really
you know understand some learning is
also you know really good sometimes
uh but if you did uh you know enjoy it
don't forget to share this video with
your friends i'd be more than happy uh
if you do share video with your friends
and you know let let's spread the
knowledge uh that we have and that's
been my primary objective and i'm sure
many of you are learning from me so
let's spread this objective uh let's
spread knowledge and share this video
with your friends and also you know
don't forget to subscribe to the channel
and don't forget to subscribe don't
forget to like this video as well so
i'll leave you here this is just another
stock video uh and every week i do give
another set of stock video video and
we'll be covering more stocks in the
future and we already four months with
the newsletter and we have 1600
subscribers so also don't forget to
subscribe to the newsletter okay so
that's it from me for today i hope
you're enjoying this video i hope you're
enjoying my channel i hope you're
enjoying my tweets on twitter
and do let me know your feedback i'd be
more than happy to understand what you
need and probably what i should be
covering more to enhance and spread
knowledge okay thank you until i see in
the next video bye